Preliminary Inventory of the United States Army Air Forces, Air Matériel Command T-2, Air Documents Division Translation Section translations
Hoover Institution Archives
United States Army Air Forces, Air Matériel Command T-2, Air Documents Division Translation Section translations
1933-1949
46025
Hoover Institution Archives
62 manuscript boxes (30.1 linear feet)
Abstracts and translations of captured German military and industrial technical reports, 1937-1945, relating to aeronautics. Includes German texts of reports in many cases. Translations made by the Air Matériel Command and by various American aeronautical companies, especially the Lockheed Aircraft Corporation. Includes Air Matériel Command reports, 1946, listing translated documents.
United States. Army Air Forces. Air Matériel Command. T-2. Air Documents Division. Translation Section.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1946.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Acquired in 1946, abstracts and translations of captured German military and industrial technical reports, tests, and statistical analysis between 1937-1945, relating to aeronautics. Includes untranslated German texts of reports, tests, and statistical analysis in many cases, on aviation and aeronautic technology. Translations and photocopies of translations made by the Air Matériel Command and by various American aeronautical companies, especially the Lockheed Aircraft Corporation. Includes Air Matériel Command reports, 1946, listing translated documents.
Materials within the collection have been maintained in the original order. Original covers have been photocopied and discarded.
Boxes (13-15, 26, 28-30, 43-45, 53, 54, 59, and 60) are translated and photocopied materials that remain in original form, as scrolls. Refer to each box’s respective container list, which are enclosed, with corresponding identification numbers as listed.
Historical note
Air Material Command was a United States Army Air Forces command, between 1944 and 1946, and United States Air Force command, between 1946 and 1961. Its headquarters were located at Write-Patterson Air Force Base, east of Dayton Ohio in Greene and Montgomery counties. The materiel division’s primary role and responsibility was procurement and research & development. The functions of research and development and logistics were operated separately during World War II until they were reunited for several years in the late 1940’s under Air Materiel Command.
Germany. Luftwaffe.; Lockheed Aircraft Corporation.; Aeronautics, Military.; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945--Technology.
- Box 1, 1946-1949
  - Scholkemeirer: "6-component tests on three swept wings with and without fuselage,", 17 January 1943 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Abbrennstumpf: "Scheiβung Flieg W 1620,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Schulz: "Aerodynamic rules for the design of jet propulsion nacelles,", 20 November 1945 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Ott: "Anti-Submarine Detection,", January 1944 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Lauer: "Description of an objective phonometer for the measurement of aircraft noise,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Buerheim: "Evaluation of the prolonged stability of the spar flange of the FW-300A long-range transport,", 29 August 1949 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Betz: "Formation of noises and their avoidance,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Bychar: "The high speed flight of tomorrow (a perspective of its difficulties),", 1949 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Hauck: "Influence of the chemical structure of synthetic materials on their mechanical properties, especially in regions of low temperatures,", 1942 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Correll: "Investigation of guide-beam control of an AA missile,", 18 February 1947 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Braun: "Investigation of slat kinematics,", circa 1948 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Luftfahrt-forschung: "Investigations on glazing materials for altitude chambers,", 17 January 1942 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Sauer: "Linearized supersonic flow around yawed bodies of revolution,", 9 December 1940 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - List of diagrams for parts on BO-R2 rocket airplane, circa 1945 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Eckert: "Measurements on pressure distribution on a deflectable rudder for the project 'Wasserfall,'", circa 1944 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Bilharz: "On single-dimensional free oscillations at non-linear restoring force,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Wegener: "On the 'S-trend' of controllability curves on the device 'Wasserfall,'", 3 March 1945 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Peucker: "Optical ultra-red proximity fuze,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Shugt and Mahrun: "Researches on pursuit-curves,", July 1946 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Küch: "Safety glass and transparent plastics for high altitude aircraft,", 9 March 1938 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Eichler: "Solution of the integral equation of Possio for the harmonically osciallating airfoil in a compressible medium by reconversion to a linear equation system,", circa 1944 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Ringleb: "Some aerodynamic relations for an airfoil in oblique flow,", 1941 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Kehl: "Subsonic and supersonic wind tunnel measurements on a model of the long-range rocket Rh Z M 5,", 29 March 1946 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Luetgebrune: "Supplements to sweep wing tests,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Translation reports and list of completed translations, 1946 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Ludwieg: "Wind tunnel tests in subsonic and supersonic regions on a model of the anti-aircraft rocket 'Rheintochter R III',", 29 March 1946 (Box-folder 1: 26)
- Box 2
  - Ringleb: "Contributions to profile classification of wings,", September 1946 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Clamann: "Decompression tests on humans,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Bychar: "The high speed flight of tomorrow (a perspective of its difficulties),", 1949 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Eisenmann: "Lateral stability of an airplane with a swept-back wing,", 21 November 1945 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Scherer: "Nose intake tests on swept wing,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Schiller: "On the photographing of oscillograms of bodies oscillating in the wind tunnel,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Haefeli: "Snow Mechanics with Hints to the Earth Structure Mechanics,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Haefeli: "Snow Mechanics with Hints to the Earth Structure Mechanics" (continued), circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Ernsthausen: "Sound field and sound output of an airscrew,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Scheubel: "The tail-less airplane in comparison to conventional types,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Dietz and Harling: "Tail wheel flutter,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Regenscheit: "Tests on a suction wing NACA 23015 with and without curved nose,", 1 December 1940 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Bausch: "Wind tunnel tests on a minimal slat,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 2: 13)
- Box 3
  - Hildenbrand and Lamme: "3- and 6- component tests on a model of ME 328 with swept wings,", 14 July 1943 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - "Brief report on comparative stability studies made on PPGF/28/3200/180/1 and PPGF/28/3200/170/1 with various tail assemblies,", 5 November 1942 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - "Brief report pertaining to a preliminary study on A4 to determine the effect of rudder enlargement on spin control,", 27 June 1942 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Vieweg: "Development of special flowmeters,", 25 February 1948 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Haehnel: "Efficiency of jamming measures against ground observation instruments,", November 1944 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Zeiler: "Experiences with various slat-kinematics of the ME 210,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Hild: "Heating of the skin and the warhead of various models A8 and A9 during flight,", 24 May 1948 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Nadler: "The influence of the expansion on the characterstics of the laval nozzle,", 22 October 1947 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Hase: "Measurement of skin temperatures,", 20 November 1947 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Oberth: "On the best division of rocket stages,", 7 January 1942 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Heybey et al: "On the damping of plane oscillations of small amplitude of an 'Arrow-Stable' shell,", 28 October 1943 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Shubert: "On the theory of stationary compression shocks,", August 1948 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Dr. Schiller: "Operating data of a supersonic wind tunnel powered with water jet injector pump 2032,", 20 December 1944 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Puffert: "Preliminary report on high velocity tests of swept wings,", 27 January 1944 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - "Pressure-distribution readings taken on a movable rudder for project 'Wasserfall',", 6 December 1944 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Schaefer: "Propagation of a two-dimensional irrotational supersonic flow along a wall,", 5 November 1942 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - H. Lindemann: "Results of measuring tests on airplane model Ju 287 from the DVL high velocity wind tunnel,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Roehren: "Strength tests on fuselage of Me 264 (long range bomber),", May 1942 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - "Studies on the propagation of spark generated detonation waves in the windtunnel,", 6 August 1945 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Ludwieg: "Swept wings at high velocities,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - von Vietinghoff - Scheel: "Test report on the investigation of flow abotu two turbine blade profiles by the aid of the interference method,", 31 May 1944 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Kehl: "Wind tunnel tests on the models of Henschel-device 'Zitterochen' at sub-and supersonic speeds,", 1 April 1946 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - Veigt, Heger and Walter: "Wind tunnel tests on wing flutter oscillations with external excitation at 2 and 3 degrees of freedom (plane problem),", circa 1945 (Box-folder 3: 23)
- Box 4
  - Hildenbrand and Lemme: "3- and 6- component measurements of a model of the ME 328 with sweptback wings,", 25 January 1946 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Lange and Wacke: "3- and 6-component tests on the pointedness series of wings of small aspect ratio,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Puffert: "3-component measurements on wing alone with sweepback & on a complete model,", 20 July 1942 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Ritter: "3-component tests on Feuerlilie F-25, in the 2.8 m. dia. high velocity tunnel of the LFA,", 12 January 1944 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Puffert: "3-component wind tunnel tests on swept wings, and on a complete model with swept wings,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Multhopp: "A swept-back wing at high speeds,", 3 October 1945 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Schwier: "Blow-out tests for lift increase on a wing of 9% thickness with slat and flap,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Truckenbrodt: "Drag measurements on nacelles of auxiliary and comparison with calculations,", 10 August 1944 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Hempel: "Drag of nacelles with strut at high Mach-numbers. Influence of form and Reynolds' no.,", 10 August 1944 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Regenscheit: "Drag reduction by suction of the boundary layer separated behind shock wave formation at high mach numbers,", 10 December 1945 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Hempel: "EF 122 - Directional stablility at high mach-numbers,", November 1943 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Münch: "EF122 half-model at high Mach-numbers. VII. Influence of length position of wing nacelle,", 18 February 1944 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Münch: "EF122 half-model tests at high mach-numbers,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Hempel: "EF 122 wing with symmetrical NACA - foil at high Mach-numbers. Influence of dihedral arrangment,", 21 January 1944 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Münch: "EF122B - tests on wing 1a at high Mach-numbers,", 3 March 1944 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - North American Aviation Inc: "Flight mechanics,", 9 February 1948 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Edelmann and Bangerter: "Heat insulating materials for exhaust turbines and pipe lines,", 17 December 1947 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Curtiss-Wright Corp: "High speed data on a small aspect ratio wing,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Göthert: "High speed measurements on a sweptback wing,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Göthert: "High velocity tests on a wing of small aspect ratio,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Busemann: "Infinitesimal conical supersonic flow,", December 1942 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Krueger: "Integration of acceleration by means of a synchronous motor,", 2 February 1948 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - Mallach: "Integration of acceleration through eddy current braking of a carriage,", 2 February 1948 (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - "List of illustrations for high velocity tests on four cambered airfoils,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 4: 24)
  - Prestele: "ME 262 - Investigations of flight characterstics at high velocities based on wind tinnel tests,", 29 July 1943 (Box-folder 4: 25)
  - Most favorable angle of divergence of a laval nozzle, 17 May 1948 (Box-folder 4: 26)
  - Bock: "New methods in German airplane construction,", 1945 (Box-folder 4: 27)
  - Heinz: "The pressure distribution on the solid of revolution WK 581 E at an angle of attack of 0 degrees, in which the formation of vortices has been taken into account,", 19 February 1948 (Box-folder 4: 28)
  - Tilch: "Pressure distribution tests on Me 262 02 B 44 foil and tailplane,", 2 April 1946 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - "Production increase by means of moving belt assembly,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 4: 30)
  - "Separation of oscillation in general differential equations for calculation of trajectories for guided missiles and for testing stability,", 13 November 1940 (Box-folder 4: 31)
  - Lange and Wacke: "Test reports of 3- and 6-component tests on the angularity series of wings of small aspect ratio,", 2 April 1946 (Box-folder 4: 32)
- Box 5
  - Knappe: "3 component tests on model of He 219,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Gropler: "Aerodynamic and structural design considerations for wings with high degree of sweepback,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Arado: "Calculations of an aero-foil with trailing edge flaps with various trailing edge angles,", August 1943 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Perlchen: "Condensation of moisture in pressure reduction valves,", 19 February 1948 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Lindemann: "Deutsche luftfahrtforschung - Untersuchungen und Mitteilung,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Plock and Eberspaecher: "Experimental welds of steel spars of the Fw-191 Bomber, and strength properties of cold-worked flange angles,", December 1941 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Lemme: "Force tests and pressure distributions on a wing with bent nose, slat, camber and extension flap,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Kraus: "Friction temperature tests on a longitudinally streamed tubular probe in subsonic and supersonic flow,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Lindemann: Graphs and diagrams, circa 1945 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Eber: "Heating of the warhead of the A4 missile during flight,", 15 October 1941 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - High speed wind tunnel measurements on NACA airfoils, July 1941 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Hackh: "Icing conditions, evaporation losses, and heat transfer characterstics of non-insulated oxygen tanks and of oxygen tanks which are installed in the A-4 missile,", 16 June 1948 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Lehmann: "Interference tests on a rectangular wing with two engine nacelles,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Investigation of a centrifugal pump, 17 May 1948 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Focke-Wulf: "Pitching moment, lift, and drag coefficients for NACA profiles 23006 to 23021", "list of reports pertaining to theoretical and experimental research work on wing profiles,", March 1942 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Technische Berichte mit Luftfahrtschrifttum des Auslandes in Ubersetzungen (untranslated), July 1944 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Lehmann: "Wind tunnel measurements on a jet engine model with a cold jet, and a wing as a boundary,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Lehmmann: "Wind tunnel measurements on jet engine models with cold jet,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 5: 18)
- Box 6
  - Jacobs: "6-component tests on four trapeze wings with sweep position,", 10 March 1944 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Test Center Rechlin: "Comparison of the lateral stability, target approach, bomb dropping characterstics and controllability of the airplane types He 111, DO 217, Ju 188, He 177 and B-17,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Kretschmer: "Conference report on wing spar construction, held at the Henschel works,", 17 October 1941 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Huber: "Development and research on impulse-type heater for the moving of gases,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Kendler: "Discussion of testing the newly developed electrically heated windows,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Hempel: "Drag of nacelles with strut at high Mach-numbers. Influence of form and Reynolds' number,", 15 December 1943 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Göthert/Kolb: "Drop-tests for the determination of drag of the bomb SC-50 at high velocities,", 15 August 1944 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Lindemann: "DVL high-speed wind-tunnel test on He 219 long range night fighter,", March 1943 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Hempel: "EF 122 wing with symmetrical NACA - foil at high Mach-numbers. Influence of dihedral arrangement,", 21 January 1944 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Doetsch and Lange: "Effect of pitching moment on elevator control,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Hornung: "Efficiency comparison of TL-drive pursuit planes,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Schneller: "Extraction from archiv reports 12/11, 12/13, and 12/14 on the wabbling motion of an arrow stable body at free flight,", 3 July 1945 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Hild: "Heating of the warhead of glider A 4 during flight,", 17 November 1941 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Göthert: "High speed measurements in D V L - high speed wind tunnel - 2.7 m diameter on a rectangular wing with diving brake corresponding to Ju 288/V 6,", January 1942 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Lindemann: "High speed measurements on the Me 262 airplanes,", September 1942 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Eckert: "Hinge moments and controllability tests on rudder no. 21 of 'Wasserfall',", circa 1945 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Küch & Perkuhn: "Investigations on the elastic properties of transparent synthetic materials,", 28 August 1940 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Guerard: "Method for considering wing stiffness in evaluating the best glider criteria,", 20 December 1939 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Krüger: "Noise problems in aviation,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - "Preliminary results on wind-tunnel tests on a series of NACA profiles with and without split flaps,", July 1941 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Göthert: "Pressure distribution and impulse loss diagrams of the airfoil 0 00 06 - 1.1 30 at high subsonic velocities,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Göthert: "Pressure distribution diagrams for the airfoil 1 35 12 - 0.55 40 at high subsonic velocities,", 2 May 1944 (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Göthert: "Pressure distribution diagrams for the airfoil 2 35 12 - 0.55 40 at high subsonic velocities,", 2 May 1944 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Horten Bros: "Stability considerations on swept wings,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Fuchs: "Tests on friction on snow,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 6: 25)
- Box 7
  - Heybey: "Analytic treatment of normal condensation shocks,", 30 March 1942 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Klein: "Built-in balance,", 15 October 1945 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Strassl: "Camber corrections for screw profiles,", 1 April 1946 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Feldmann: "Compressibility effects in aviation,", 1946 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Mangler: "Compressible boundry layers on bodies of revolution,", 15 March 1946 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Wielandt: "Contributions to the mathematical treatment of complex eigenvalue problems. II. The iterative method for not self-adjoint linear eigenvalue probelms,", 1 April 1946 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Giessler, Ludwieg & Cox: "Control apparatus for the project "Wasserfall" 144 g. Kdos.,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Kress: "Econcomic manufacturing accuracies,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Lindemann: "High speed measurements on a Me 163B tailless airplane model with nontwisted wings,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Gothert: "The increase of drag of profiles in the range of high subsonic speeds,", February 1944 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - A.D.D., D.4.P.: "Interrogation of Dipl. Ing. E. A. Marquard,", 27 March 1946 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Braun: "Investigation of slat kinematics,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Tillmann: "Investigations of some particularities of turbulent boundary layers on plates,", 27 August 1945 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Luetgebrune: "Investigation of the wake and drag of straight and sweep-back wings,", 20 September 1942 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Seiferth: "Investigation on an airscrew with swept back blade tips at high tip speed,", 30 November 1945 (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Jacker: "Investigations on glazing materials for altitude chambers,", 1942 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Friedricks: "Investigations on glide-angle control,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Haefeli: "The mechanics of snow, with hints to the Earth structure mechanics,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - Harant: "Method to produce hydrogen peroxide (H202),", 30 November 1945 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - Stuper: "Modern problems of airscrew aerodynamics,", 15 April 1946 (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - Seiferth: "The most important experimental research work of the last time and proposals about reports still to be written,", 25 June 1945 (Box-folder 7: 21)
  - Shugt: "New method and equipment for continuously tracking a flying target with 3 bearing axes,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 7: 22)
  - Weber: "On Betz's computation of the diffuser losses,", 1 April 1946 (Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Tollmien: "On the behaviour of a flow along a wall at the outer edge of its boundary layer,", 15 March 1946 (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Reichardt: "On the determination of favourable shapes of bodies for high speed by cavitation tests,", 1 April 1946 (Box-folder 7: 25)
  - Maier: "Problems of the swivellable airplane wheel,", 1943 (Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Kussner: "Proposals for future resarch work,", 31 January 1946 (Box-folder 7: 27)
  - Kuch: "Recent investigations on glasses and sealing materials for altitude chambers,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 7: 28)
  - Kuchemann: "Remarks on the Betz-Knoller Effect,", 15 March 1946 (Box-folder 7: 29)
  - Fluegge: "Report by Dr Fluegge on the pent aerythritol plant,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 7: 30)
  - Schultheis: "Report on work in connection with explosives,", December 1945 (Box-folder 7: 31)
  - Baeuerle: "Supplement of the report of the institute "wind tunnels" of June 25th 1945, p. 59: "Design of velocity meters at the Ava Goettingen",", 1 April 1946 (Box-folder 7: 32)
- Box 8
  - Lange-Nacke: "3- and 6- component tests on the pointedness series of wings of small aspect ratio,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Liess: "3-component tests on the Rheinmetal devices R 100 M2 and R 100 M3 in the supersonic wind tunnel,", circa 1945 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Haffel: "Additional three component measurements on the finned projectile model A4V12,", 11 March 1943 (Box-folder 8: 3)